KARABO **MTSWENI**

PROCESS ENGINEER

CONTACT



www.linkedin.com/in/karabo**é-è** mtsweni-91149b163



(078) 150-1859



mtswenikarabo00@gmail.com



6 Alexander Road, Newton Park Port Elizabeth, 6000

SKILLS

Technical Competencies

- **VDA PSCR**
- Microsoft Excel (Advanced)
- ISO 9001:2015(QMS)
- Matlab
- Lean Six Sigma
- SYSPRO 8
- **AutoCAD**
- Shopware
- Core Tools I

Behavioral Competencies

- **Problem Solving**
- Critical Thinking
- Accountability
- Risk Management
- Mentoring
- **Decision Making**
- Problem solving
- Adaptive

SUMMARY

Process Engineer with two years' experience in the automotive industry, improving manufacturing processes through continuous improvement. Experienced in process control, PPAP, APQP and Change management. Highly proficient in problem solving, project management and risk management. Committed to boosting process performance and achieving sustainable results.

EXPERIENCE

September 2023 - Present

Process Engineer

Adient PPC Pty Ltd, Port Elizabeth, Eastern Cape

- Perform data analysis, root cause analysis and identify and implement process improvements to support issue resolution and optimizing production processes to eliminate losses, improve quality, capacity, throughput and conversion cost
- Duties include managing process or product changes throughout the plant as identified via ECRs/Aeko's
- Experience in Problem Solving Techniques (DMAIC), QMS, SPC, Poke Yoke, Kaizen.
- Knowledge of Lean manufacturing, Value stream mapping, Total Preventative Maintenance etc.
- Key functions include day-to-day production and quality support, facilities and tooling development, project management and introducing new products/options into production
- Assist and/or update, create, verify and maintain Bill of Materials (BOM's), PFMEAs, Control Plans and SOPs.

July 2022 - June 2023

Quality Assurance Intern

Adient PPC Pty Ltd, Port Elizabeth, Eastern Cape

- Supervised a team of weld analysis technicians at the Material Testing Lab, analyzing weld penetration through metallographically studies and analysis.
- Conducting process optimization and quality investigations.
- Worked closely with Production to identify and resolve quality system deficiencies, maintain calibration documentation for instruments and equipment.
- Knowledge in process capabilities studies including SPC analysis of dimensional reports.
- Ensured compliance with customer and global standards such as ISO, VDA 6.3, IATF and CQI.

EDUCATION

June 2024 - Present

Six Sigma Green Belt (DMAIC)

2KO Africa

February 2018 - May 2022

Bachelor of Engineering Technology in Physical Metallurgy

University of Johannesburg, Johannesburg

Relevant Coursework

- Casting Design
- Engineering Drawing
- Mechanical Deformation
- Material Testing
- Welding Technology

Extracurricular Activities

Community Engagement (Volunteering)

CERTIFICATIONS

- ISO 9001:2015 Quality management system auditor certified.
- Six Sigma White Belt Certified
- Project Management Certified with Management & Strategy Institutes
- Microsoft Excel Intermediate Certified.
- VDA PSCR Certified

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded and recognized for being a game changer under the YES Top 35 Under 35.
- Coordinated with management to introduce the ECR/DA system onto SYSPRO, making the organization TISAX Compliant.
- Rewarded by management and CI Team for successful reduction in the usage of grease on the assembly line by introducing a more robust and deficient method of application.
- Collaborated with HSEE to improve on toxic chemicals usage safety and ergonomics in the Material Testing Lab.

REFERENCES

Reference list will be provided upon request.